AJIN: DEMI-HUMAN
Do you sleep well?
深く眠れるかい？
傷は癒せたかい？
Did your wounds heal?
Just cos' they say the night is lonely
夜が寂しいからって
無理して
誰かを愛さないで
You don't have to force yourself
To love someone
They say I'm dreaming
夢を見る事だって
咽び泣く事だって
They say I'm sobbing
知りもしないまま
死んでみたって
They say I tried to die without knowing
Did you manage to hide?
上手に隠れたかい？
息は潜めたかい？
Did you hold your breath?
Just cos' they say it's tough now
You don't have to force yourself to change
今が苦しいからって
無理して自分変えないで
Even a brave savage
勇敢な蛮人だって
悩める子羊だって
Even a troubled lamb
回り道して生きているって
They are just wandering through life
So I don't stand out
目立たないように
So I can put up with it
堪えられるように
思考回路はまだ
止めないように
So my train of thought won't stop yet
Tonight run away, run a way
It's unbelievable
今宵 RUN A WAY  RUN A WAY
嘘みたいだ
誰かこの手
掴んでくれよ
Someone take my hand
The tomorrow we can't see
Doesn't have to come
見えない明日は来なくていい
今はただ　眠りたい
Now I just want to sleep
BUT WHEN IT COMES DOWN TO IT,
YOU STILL WANT THEM TO HELP YOU...
YOU'RE THE WORST KIND OF TRASH...
Go around the back!
Don't let them get away!
裏からも回れ！
絶対に逃がすな！
Search thoroughly inside the shrine, too.
社殿内も くまなく捜せ
Two of you go that way.
Check inside the thickets, too.
（警官）
おい そっち ２人で行け
雑木林の中もだ
Where is Kei Nagai?
永井圭は どこだ！
Mr. Araki! Over here...!
荒木さん！　こっちに…
（荒木）
あ？　何だ？
What is it?
（ハエの羽音）
My God.
ひどいな
-Nagai did this?
-No.
永井が… これを？
（戸崎）
違いますね
おっ…
Mr. Tosaki.
（荒木）
どうも… 戸崎さん
It would seem to be the work of the man
who contacted Kei Nagai.
恐らくは 永井圭と接触した男の
仕業でしょう
ま… まだ どこかに
隠れている可能性もある
They could still be hiding somewhere.
Conduct a search of the shrine!
神社内を徹底的に調べろ！
（警官）は… はい！
（戸崎）無駄ですよ
-Yes, sir!
-It's no use.
If they were still here,
you would not be standing here alive.
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
もし この場にいるなら―
あなた方が
無事で済むはずがありません
（荒木）
は？
What?
（携帯の着信音）
ふぅ…
It's Tosaki.
戸崎です
永井圭の行方を見失いました
We've lost track of Kei Nagai.
He should be with Hat right now.
現在は帽子と一緒のはず
We'll continue our search.
（戸崎）
行方を追わせます
That won't be needed.
（秘書）
その必要はありません
Kei Nagai is already being transported.
永井圭は既に移送中です
30分ほど前 山梨の消防署前に
倒れていたそうです
He was found collapsed
in front of a fire station in Yamanashi
around 30 minutes ago.
You'll be filled in at the lab.
詳しくは研究所で
Wha--? What did you say?!
な… 何ですって？
So, apparently Kei Nagai is a variant.
（大臣）
永井圭は別種だそうだな
Just like Shinya Nakamura.
中村慎也(なかむらしんや)と同じ… か
According to the report, that is.
（秘書）
報告によれば… ですが
He'll be a valuable sample.
（大臣）
貴重なサンプルだ
Take good care of him.
丁重に扱いたまえ
Very well, sir.
かしこまりました
I don't get it.
なぜだ？
帽子に裏切られたのか？
Did Hat betray him?
Sorry about that.
（田中功次(たなかこうじ)）
すいませんね…
No, no, it made it much more realistic.
いやいや リアリティがあって
よかったよ
まだ 狙撃は下手くそなもんで…
I need more practice with my aiming.
But if we want to bring him over
to our side,
でも こっち側に
引き入れるのが目的なら―
couldn't we have just beaten him up
and made him listen?
フクロにして言うこと聞かせても
よかったんじゃないすか？
はぁ？　それじゃあ
我々が恨みを買うだけだよ
All that would've accomplished
is getting him to hate us.
Well, yeah, but...
まあ そうですけど…
You know better than anyone exactly
what goes on there, right?
あそこで何が行われるか
それは 君が
一番よく知っているだろう
くっ… ぐっ…
フッ 人間への憎悪 復讐(ふくしゅう)心
Hatred of humans... thirst for revenge...
We gave him over to the humans
so he could learn it first-hand.
その全てを植え付けるために
彼を人間側に差し出したんだ
Where am I?
（圭）
ここは…
What happened?
どうなったんだ？
Where's Mr. Sato?
佐藤さんは？
こ… これは！
What's this?
A blindfold?!
目隠し？
（うめき声）
I... I've been caught?!
僕は… 捕まったのか！？
（うめき声）
The subject's DNA...
（野村(のむら)）
被験体のＤＮＡは…
matches the DNA taken from the
site of the truck accident.
トラック事故の現場に
残されたものと一致
He's definitely an Ajin.
間違いなく亜人だな
Heart rate and body temperature
are normal.
（近藤(こんどう)）
心拍数 体温 共に異常なし
Then let's begin.
（田原(たはら)）
よし 始めよう
（圭）
うっ… ううっ… うっ…
（切断する音）
（うめき声）
-Forceps.
-Here.
（野村）
鉗子(かんし)を
（うめき声）
Cutting brachial artery circulation.
（野村）
上腕動脈を止血
Send this to Iwasaki.
これ 岩崎(いわさき)さんに送っておいて
It's to compare with the arm post
regeneration.
再生前の腕と見比べるらしい
This time we'll be watching brain activity
as we go.
今度は脳の活動を観察しながらだ
We can estimate how many times he's died
at this point by his reaction to the pain.
痛みの反応で これまで
何回死んだか予測出来る
（切断する音）
（圭）ううっ！
（うめき声）
（近藤）
うーん… 波が大きいな
Those are big waves.
（野村）
まだ あまり死んでないようだ
Apparently he hasn't died much yet...
just a few times.
数回程度かな
よし もっと痛みを与えてみよう
Okay, let's put him
through some more pain.
（うめき声）
（たたく音）
（戸崎）ん？
（野村）
あっ？
What was that?
（近藤）
何だ？
（野村）
あ…
What is it?
（若井(わかい)）
どうした？
（野村）
ガラスの傷って
最初からありましたっけ？
Have those scratches always been
on the glass?
（若井）
ああ 最初からあったが
Yeah, they've always been there. Why?
I see. Sorry.
（野村）
そうですか　すみません
Continue.
（若井）
続けたまえ
Amazing, to scratch glass this thick.
（太居(ふとい)）
すごいな
この厚さのガラスを削るとは
So, this is the power of a variant.
（岸(きし)）
これが別種の力か…
-Can you see it?
-Yes. It's right there.
見えるか？
はい　すぐそこに
Was that made by ultrasonic waves
or something?
（岸）
この傷は超音波か何かか？
（若井）
違うでしょう
田中が奪われた時は―
Not likely.
When Tanaka was taken, there were
marks like footprints left at the scene.
襲撃現場に足跡のようなものが
残っていました
（コウマ）
フン 足の生えた幽霊でも
いるってのか？
So, you're saying there are ghosts
with feet?
Inflict some more pain and let's observe.
（太居）
もっと痛みを与えて
観察してみよう
（圭のうめき声）
Why doesn't Nagai
attack the researchers?
なぜ 永井は研究員を攻撃しない？
It's possible that he's not aware
of his own power.
力を自覚していない
可能性があります
Or his link with the black ghost
may be unstable as well.
黒い幽霊とのリンクが
不安定なのかも
What do you mean?
どういうことだ？
It's like making a phone call in an area
with poor reception, for example.
例えば 電波の悪い所で
通話する感じです
So, it's possible he could attack
at some point--
なので いずれ
彼らを攻撃する可能性も…
What about now?
今は？
え？
What is it doing right now?
今は何をしている？
Right now it's...
今は… その…
looking at you, Mr. Tosaki.
戸崎さんを見てます
（戸崎）
フン 偉そうに…
You insolent little...
Do you realize how you all have
destroyed my life plans?!
お前らのおかげで 私の人生設計が
どれだけ崩れたと思ってる！
Watch very closely, Shimomura.
よく見ておけよ 下村君
え？
The only reason
you're on this side of the glass
君が ここで
そうしていられるのも―
is because I'm hiding you from them.
私が秘密裏に
かくまっているからにすぎない
Do your work... or else you'll...
しっかり働けよ
さもなくば…
君も ああなる
end up like that as well.
はっ！　ああっ…
（太居）
そろそろ反応が鈍くなってきたな
His reactions are growing sluggish.
Time to reset him.
（若井）
リセットするか
Okay, kill him for now and take a break.
よし 一度 殺して休憩にしよう
（近藤）
ふぅ… よし 休憩だ
-Okay, break time.
-We made a lot of progress.
（野村）
だいぶ はかどったな
How could they?
（圭）
ひどい…
Why is this...
どうして僕が…
...happening to me?
こんな目に…
-Okay, I'll leave the rest to you.
-Fine.
（近藤）
じゃあ 後は よろしく
（野村）
ああ
All I wanted...
was to be an upstanding person.
（圭）
僕は ただ―
立派な人間に
なりたかっただけなのに
This is...
こんなの…
just too horrible.
ひどすぎる
...What's wrong?
（田中）
どうした？
I thought that you didn't want
to become like me?
俺みたいのには
なりたくなかったんじゃないのか？
（圭）
はっ… うっ…
（田中）
フッ あの時―
Looking at me with such scorn.
さげすむように見てたのは
何だったんだ？
（圭）
ロクでもない人間がいるのは
確かです
There are definitely horrible humans
out there.
でも 佐藤さんと同じで―
But like you, Mr. Sato,
I don't see humans as enemies.
僕も人間を敵視するつもりは
ありません
Where did your righteousness go?
（田中）
正義感ぶった
あれは何だったんだ？
Do you finally get it?
やっと分かったか？
You knew nothing of hell.
You were just trying to look cool.
てめえは地獄も知らねぇで
カッコつけてただけだ
はぁ はぁ はぁ… ううっ！
（田中）
他人を見下してるくせに―
You look down on others...
but when it comes down to it,
you still want them to help you.
いざとなったら助けを求める
最低なクズ
You're the worst kind of trash.
それが お前だよ
That's right. Kill!
そうだ… やれ！
Kill!
殺せ！
Embrace your true nature!
本当の自分になれ！
（野村）
あっ… ん？　風？
Was that the wind...?
Why did you stop?!
なぜ やめる！？
カイは もう 助けに来ない！
Kai's not coming to help you anymore!
佐藤だって
捕まってるかもしれねぇんだぞ！
And Sato might have been captured!
If I did it...
（圭）
これをしたら―
カイに嫌われるかもしれない
Kai might hate me...
I think...
彼だけは 裏切るわけには
いかないんだと思う
...Kai's the only one I can't betray.
Even though they're doing
all of this to you?
（田中）
こんなことまでされてんだぞ？
Killing one person wouldn't count
as a betrayal!!
１人殺したぐらいで
裏切りになるかよ
No.
（圭）
違う…
フッ もし 誰かを殺せば
二度と普通の暮らしには戻れない
If you kill someone...
you could never go back
to "living a normal life."
-That's what you're afraid of.
-No!
お前は それが嫌なだけ…
（圭）
違う！
フッ 図星か
-Hit the nail on the head, huh?
-No!
違う！
Kai.
カイは…
Kai risked his life for me...
カイは こんな僕に
命を懸けてくれたんだ
for someone like me.
たった１つしかない命を
He risked the only life he has.
でも 僕は
命を懸けることが出来ない
But I'm...
not even able to risk my life.
So...
だから…
So, if I don't risk everything else
I have...
命以外の全てを懸けなきゃ―
I won't be able to make it up to him.
割に合わないんだ
（刺さる音）
（圭）
はっ！
Okay, time for round two.
（野村）
よし 後半戦いくぞ
（圭）
あ… あ… はぁっ… はぁっ…
Our orders from above are just to cause
as much pain as possible.
（田原）
上の命令は―
“とにかく痛みを与えろ”
とのことだ
Okay, let's start
with the teeth this time.
（近藤）
じゃ 今度は歯からいくぞ
（圭）
はっ… はっ… はっ…
（ドリルの音）
（圭）うっ… ううっ！
Here's what you asked for.
（猫沢(ねこざわ)）
頼まれていた物です
Sorry to make you come up
with all these supplies, Mr. Nekozawa.
悪いね 猫沢さん
いろいろ調達させちゃって
Not at all.
I'm glad to help a valued client.
（猫沢）
いえいえ
大切なお得意さんですから
In that case, our goods are in here.
それじゃ うちの商品は
ここに入ってるので
I look forward to working with you again.
また よろしくお願いします
And you as well.
（佐藤）
こちらこそ
（ドアの開閉音）
（手下）
ちょ… 猫沢さん
Hey, Mr. Nekozawa!
Aren't you going to check its contents?
中身 確認しなくていいんすか？
-I trust him.
-Trust?
信用してる
信用って…
肝臓と腎臓が10個に 心臓まで
10 livers, 10 kidneys, even a heart.
Are they really in there...?
それだけの物が 本当に…
ああ　間違いなく入ってる
Yeah. They're definitely there.
Where would he get them all?
（手下）
どっから そんな物を…
Who knows?
さあな　でも
あの人は必ず持ってくんだよ
However, that man always delivers.
Even if it kills him.
死んでもな
（ざわめき）
Dr. Ikuya Ogura's car
has just now arrived.
（キャスター）
ただいま オグラ･イクヤ博士の
車両が到着しました
This is his second official visit
to Japan...
博士の来日と視察は―
国内２例目の田中捕獲時に続き
二度目となります
and the second Ajin captured
since Tanaka.
Ever since biophysicist Dr. Ogura went
to the U.S. in 1999,
生物物理学者である
オグラ博士は―
99年に渡米して以来―
he has been known as an authority
on Ajin research.
亜人研究の権威として
知られています
Unfortunate weather.
（佐藤）
あいにくの天気だねぇ
They're harder to control in the rain.
雨の中じゃ
あれの操作はしにくくなる
Tanaka, get to work on Plan C.
田中君は作戦Ｃ
Abducting some doctor called Ogura, right?
オグラとかいう博士の誘拐ですね
I'll take Plan B.
私は作戦Ｂ
永井圭君の救出担当だ
Rescuing Kei Nagai.
So, then, how shall we storm the castle?
さて どうすれば城を落とせるか
The answer is simple.
答えは単純　敵の想定する火力を
上回ればいいんだよ
We attack the enemy with more firepower
than they're expecting.
So, we use everything we've got...
今 私たちが持てる最大の火力で
押し潰す
to roll right over them.
世界各国の亜人研究は
競争状態ですが―
Countries all over the world are competing
with their research on Ajins...
but Japan and the U.S.
have a cooperative research agreement.
日米の研究機関は
協力関係を結んでおり
Dr. Ogura's visit to Japan
has been reported as a part of that--
オグラ博士の来日も
その一環として報じられています
Looks like we have our VIP.
（太居）
ＶＩＰが おいでなすったな
（若井）
フン ただの能なしだよ
He's just an idiot.
He doesn't seem popular here.
随分な言い方ですね
This thing with Japan and the U.S...
日米の協力関係など
表向きの報道にすぎない
is nothing more than a front.
In actuality, we're being forced
into providing them with information.
実際は一方的な情報提供を
強制されている
そうなんですか？
Really?
事実 国内初の亜人は
アメリカ側に奪われた
In fact, the first Ajin in this country
was stolen by the Americans.
So, it's no wonder the researchers
might complai--
学者連中が不満をこぼすのも…
（衝撃音）
（どよめき）
（若井）
な… 何だ これは？　地震か？
Wha--? What's going on? An earthquake?
（コウマ）
いや 爆発だ
No, an explosion.
This is the security office!
There's an intruder!
（モニター音声：警備員）
こちら 警備室！
侵入者です！
帽子の男が侵入してきました！
The man in the hat has gotten inside!
（戸崎）
永井を助けに来た？
見捨てておいて？
Did he come to rescue Nagai
after leaving him behind?
We're going to counterattack!
（警備員）
すぐに反撃します！
待て！　殺すな！
そいつは亜人だ！
Wait! Don't kill him! He's an Ajin!
（銃声）
（警備員）うっ！
（どよめき）
そこにいるのかな？　トザキ君
Are you there? Tosaki.
くっ…
You won't understand
the actual reason I'm here.
私が どうしてここに来たか
君には まだ分かるまい
だが 今夜―
But tonight...
there will be a dramatic change
in the Japanese Ajin situation.
日本の亜人事情は大きく覆る
CALL DISCONNECTED
（コウマ）
はぁ… どうするつもりだ？
戸崎
What are you going to do, Tosaki?
Kei Nagai hasn't shown his variant power
since the first day of experimentation.
（岸）
永井圭は 初日の実験以降
別種の力を見せていない
（太居）
このまま永井を奪われたら
貴重な研究材料が…
If Nagai is stolen,
we'll lose valuable research material.
（戸崎）
警備を大幅に増やしています
We've greatly reinforced our security.
If just a single tranquilizer dart
hits its mark...
麻酔銃が１発
当たりさえすれば…
there may be collateral damage...
何十人犠牲になろうと
我々の勝ちです
but our victory will be sealed.
I grant you the effectiveness
of the tranquilizers.
（コウマ）
確かに麻酔の有効性は認める
だが なぜ殺さない？
But why don't you kill him?
If things go wrong we could
be in danger ourselves!
下手すれば
我々にまで危険が及ぶんだぞ！
Remember the incident
with Shinya Nakamura?
中村慎也の件をお忘れですか？
（コウマ）
うっ！
（戸崎）
下手に亜人を殺せば
また惨劇が繰り返される
If we carelessly kill an Ajin,
another tragedy could occur.
Killing them is a worst-case scenario!
亜人の殺害は
最悪の事態になりかねない
Hurry! Go around the back!
（警備員）
早く！　後ろに回れ
そっち もっと散開しろ！
Deploy more over there!
順番に１発ずつだ！
全員が一度に撃つな！
Fire one at a time!
Don't fire all at once!
If he's hit with too many tranquilizers
he could die of shock!
麻酔を投与しすぎると
ショック死の可能性もある
（警備員）くそっ！
（警備員）安全装置解除 確認しろ！
Make sure the safety's off!
（銃声）
（警備員）うっ…
あっ…
-He's coming!
-Here I come!
来るぞ！
いくよー！
Aim carefully!
（警備員）
よく狙え！
うっ…
（銃声）
（警備員）
よし！
All right.
（警備員たちの悲鳴）
ふぅ… あれを出すまでもないね
Didn't even have to use it.
Well, then, Nagai... I've come to get you.
さて 永井君　お迎えだよ
（岸たち）
ああ…
Close the emergency bulkhead!
き… 緊急隔壁を閉めろ！
ここまで侵入させる気か！
Do you want him walking in here?
Just who is that Ajin?!
あの亜人は何者だ！
The only thing I know
is that he took Tanaka from us before,
私が知り得るのは
やつが以前に田中を奪い―
and now he is trying to steal Kei Nagai.
今は永井圭を
奪おうとしていることだけです
Damn it! From what we can see
on the screen,
（コウマ）
くそっ
（岸）
映像を見たかぎり
別種の力は使ってないようだね
he doesn't seem to be using
his variant power.
Why didn't he use it?
（若井）
なぜ 使わなかったんでしょう？
It caused a great deal of casualties
when he came for Tanaka.
田中の時は あれの力で
多くの犠牲者が出たはずです
使わなかったのではなく
そう見えなかっただけとか
Maybe he did use it,
but we just didn't see it.
Of course you wouldn't see it.
（オグラ･イクヤ）
見えなかったも何も―
Humans aren't capable of seeing it.
人間に あれを見ることは出来ない
（田中）
ん？　ちっ 逃がしたか
He got away.
（オグラ）
ふぅ…
Man, why all the commotion?
ったく… なんで
こんなに騒がしいんだ？
Even though the great Ikuya Ogura is here.
このオグラ･イクヤ様が
来たってのに
I'm sorry, it's an emergency.
すみません 緊急事態でして
ちっ 禁煙だぞ
You can't smoke in here.
Dr. Ogura, what did you mean when you said
that humans can't see the variant power?
（コウマ）
オグラ博士
あんたは さっき 別種の力は
人間に見えないと言ったな
それは どういうことだ？
You were talking about IBMs, right?
君たちは ＩＢＭの話を
してたんじゃないのか？
IBM?
（岸）
ＩＢＭ？
That's what they call the variant power
in the U.S. I think it stands for--
（若井）
別種の力を合衆国では
そう呼ぶんですよ　確か…
（オグラ）
インビジブル･ブラック･マター
Invisible Black Matter.
IBMs can't be seen by humans,
but they're shaped like us.
ＩＢＭは
人間の目に見えないくせに―
人間の形をしてる
最高にクールなやつさ
They're really freaking cool.
How ridiculous.
また 馬鹿なことを…
では 別種の力とは
霊的な何かだというわけか？
So, this variant power...
it's like a ghost or something?
陸佐
Colonel... are you some sort of idiot?
馬鹿かね 君は
（コウマ）
なっ…
IBMs aren't psychic powers
or ghosts or anything.
ＩＢＭは超能力でも幽霊でもない
They're solid matter.
物質だ
Matter?
物質？
Well, then, Nagai.
さて 永井君
Let's see how you've turned out.
君は どう仕上がるかな？
Tanaka, do you understand...
田中君 分かるかい？
助けに来たんだ
I'm here to rescue you.
（田中）
うっ ううっ くっ ううっ…
Right. That's good.
（佐藤）
そう それでいい
く… くくっ… ううっ…
（刺す音）
Nagai... do you understand...
永井君 分かるかい？
助けに来たんだ
I'm here to rescue you?
How long... have I been here?
どのぐらい…
僕は ここに？
Let's see.
そうだな…
Over ten days, I believe.
10日以上は いたかな
Ten, that's all?
それしか―
It seems like more.
経ってないのか
うっ…
（泣き声）
Mr. Sato.
佐藤さん…
I'm so sorry to have caused you
such trouble.
お手数おかけして すみません
Well, this was...
（佐藤）
この仕上がりは失敗だな…
a failure.
TO BE CONTINUED
If my wish would come true
願い叶(かな)うなら
もう一度
Once again
I wanna touch your heart
君の心に
触れていたい
No matter how dark it gets
どんな闇でも
探してるんだ
I'll be searching
For my one
たったひとつの
光を
And only light
As I look up to the stars
Even though you are far
遠いけど
You're looking up at the same starry sky
同じ星空　見上げてる
In the sky of my heart
心の空には
雫(こぼ)れ落ちそうな
It's about to spill over
Your smile and
君の笑顔と
ぬくもり
Your warmth
Hear me
Until I went away and
Faced the lonely days
愛することの意味なんて
I thought I could understand
What it means to love
分かってたつもりだった
Feeling everything that
Was right in front of me
大切なもの失って
Losing something precious
Realizing real love
本当の愛に気付いて
I'll tell you now
I'll tell you now,
Just how close you are